Finding Aid for University of Michigan. Dept. of Medicine and Surgery Theses, 1851-1878
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Medical Theses
  - Class of 1858
    - Meads, Mordecai Louis (d. 1891), "Sanguification", 1858 (Reel 6)
    - Smith, Sidney S., "Acute Pneumonia", 1858 (Reel 6)
    - Spaulding, David (d. 1904), "Therapeutical Indications", 1858 (Reel 6)
    - Thomas, Daniel Eben (d. 1903), "Continued Fever", 1858 (Reel 6)
    - Ward, Edgar Burt (d. 1899), "Congestion", 1858 (Reel 6)
    - Winslow, Enoch Marcellus (d. 1898), "Hygiene", 1858 (Reel 6)
    - Wood, Eugene Halsey (d. 1907), "Medical Onomatology", 1858 (Reel 6)
  - Class of 1859
    - Breakey, William Fleming (d. 1915), "Irrational Medicine", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Chase, Byron S. (d. 1878), "Scirrhus", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Coller, Eli Holman (d. 1903), "The Kidneys and their Secretion", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Elliott, David Sanders (d. 1869), "The Hygienic Management of Children", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Everett, Robert Augustus (d. 1897), "Dislocations of the Femur", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Flower, Cornelius (d. 1890), "The Heart and the Circulation", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Frink, Charles Safford (d. 1893), "The Formation of Carbonic Acid in the System and the Mode in which its Elimination is Effected", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Hill, Henry Clay (d. 1901), "Valvular Disease of the Heart", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Hobart, Andrew Jackson (d. 1895), "Balneology", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Longshaw, William (d. 1865), "Physiology of Fecundation", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Loring, Park Holland (d. 1865), "The Morbid and Curative Effects of the Loss of Blood", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - North, John Duboise (d. 1909), "Dislocations", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Pilcher, Elijah Holmes (d. 1889), "Neuralgia", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Randolph, Jonas Bevington (d. 1867), "Malignant Growths", 1859 (Reel 6)
    - Raymond, Mahlon Harrison (d. 1896), "Scarlet Fever", 1859 (Reel 7)
    - Rynd, Charles (d. 1884), "The History, Pathology and Treatment of Epidemic Cholera", 1859 (Reel 7)
    - Sherwood, William Theodore (d. 1911), "Typhoid Fever", 1859 (Reel 7)
    - Shoemaker, John M. (d. 1891), "Action and Therapeutical Indications of Emetics", 1859 (Reel 7)
    - Smith, Henry (d. 1915), "Vaccine Disease", 1859 (Reel 7)
    - Stevenson, Samuel (d. 1912), "Pneumonia", 1859 (Reel 7)
    - Torgason, Gregory, "Rational Medicine", 1859 (Reel 7)
    - Tyler, Dean Merrill (d. 1900), "Acute Hydrocephalus", 1859 (Reel 7)
    - Willson, James Caldwell (d. 1912), "The Primary Action of Zymotic Poisons", 1859 (Reel 7)
  - Class of 1860
    - Bowen, George Washington (d. 1908), "Animal Nutrition", 1860 (Reel 7)
    - Brown, Solomon Clay (d. 1894), "Carbon", 1860 (Reel 7)
    - Cole, Alvin Janes (d. 1903), "The Modes of Death", 1860 (Reel 7)
    - Comstock, Nathan F. (d. 1862), "Climate", 1860 (Reel 7)
    - Fellows, Milton Alexander (d. 1863), "Histology of Nervous Tissue and Structure of the Nervous System", 1860 (Reel 7)
    - Foye, Johnson Ephraim (d. 1884), "Blood Corpuscle", 1860 (Reel 7)
    - Gilkeson, Boyd Milo (d. 1865), "Causes, Symptoms and Treatment of Amenorrhea", 1860 (Reel 7)
    - Gilmore, Moses Rumsey (d. 1902), "Respiration", 1860 (Reel 7)
    - Haun, Edgar (d. 1901), "Dyspepsia", 1860 (Reel 7)
    - Hesse, Bernhard (d. 1908), "Electricity, its Relation to Life and its Use as a Therapeutical Agent", 1860 (Reel 7)
    - Lord, Frederick Augustus (d. 1872), "Evolution of the Circulatory Apparatus and of the Plan of the Circulation of the Blood", 1860 (Reel 8)
    - Loree, Darius Williams (d. 1919), "Practical Medicine", 1860 (Reel 8)
    - Lyster, Henry Francis (d. 1894), "Veritrum Viride", 1860 (Reel 8)
    - Plant, William Tomlinson (d. 1898), "Craniology", 1860 (Reel 8)
    - Pratt, Samuel Ralzaman (d. 1911), "Modus Operandi of Medicine", 1860 (Reel 8)
    - Richards, George Rawson (d. 1895), "The Chemical Phenomena of Vegetation" [Degree granted in 1861], 1860 (Reel 8)
    - Rogers, Obadiah (d. 1889), "Amputation", 1860 (Reel 8)
    - Sadler, George (d. 1903), "Causes, Symptoms and Treatment of Scarlatina", 1860 (Reel 8)
    - Shewmaker, James Matteson (d. ca. 1880), "Auscultation", 1860 (Reel 8)
    - Tickner, Ambrose R. (d. 1862), "The Integrity of the Vascular System, a Necessary Condition to Health", 1860 (Reel 8)
    - Twiss, Edward (d. 1895), "The Vital Force and its Manifestation in the Animal Organism", 1860 (Reel 8)
    - Voorhees, George Washington (d. 1867), "Dysentery", 1860 (Reel 8)
    - West, M. Calvin (d. 1891), "Diphtheria", 1860 (Reel 8)
  - Class of 1861
    - Allen, Abijah Marvin (d. 1919), "A Few Brief Remarks on Hygiene", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Allen, Albert Langdon, "Vital Force in Nutrition", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Bailey, William Worth (d. 1913), "Syphilis", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Barnes, George (d. 1873), "Pathology of the Poisonous Effects of Alcohol", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Barrett, Joseph Ellis (d. 1901), "Typhoid Fever", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Beck, William Herod (d. 1914), "Syphilis", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Bissell, Elias Leavitt (d. 1905), "The Influence of the Mind Over the Body", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Burton, Caswell Riddles (d. 1862), "Pernicious Fever", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Burton, William Anderson (d. 1908), "The Human Heart", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Chapin, Andrew Bliss (d. 1902), "Chloroform", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Chase, Milton, "Water, its Physiological, Prophylactic, and Therapeutical Powers and Uses, 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Clark, Anson Timothy (d. 1915), "Acute Abscess", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Cleland, Henry Alexander (d. 1911), "Some Features in the Pathology of Inflammation", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Crawford, Samuel Knox (d. 1902), "Chloroform in Relation to Medical Jurisprudence", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Crosier, Edward Stokoe (d. 1891), "Embryonic Development", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Curtis, Warren Blair (d. 1920), "Veratrum Viride", 1861 (Reel 8)
    - Emerson, William Henry (d. 1863), "Bilious Remittent Fever", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Fisher, William F. (d. 1896), "The Lachrymal Gland and its Secretion", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Fraser, William Edwin, "Insanity", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Galbraith, Franklin Benjamin (d. 1903), "Chronic Valvular Disease of the Heart", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Howell, Charles (d. 1903), "Auscultation", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Hutchinson, William Lewis (d. 1908), "The Physical Examination of the Heart", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Hutchison, John Harmon (d. 1897), "Animal Nutrition", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Jones, James Thomas (d. 1898), "Chronic Inflammation (sic) and Ulceration of the Cervix Uteri", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Kennedy, John (d. 1878), "Acute Peritonitis", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Kimberly, Dennis (d. 1864), "Pernicious Fever", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Koon, Sherman Jacob, "The Renal Apparatus and Secretion", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Lacey, Seth C. (d. 1902), "Hygiene", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - LaMonte, Austin (d. 1918), "Circulation of the Blood", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - LeBaron, Robert, "Asiatic Cholera", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Morris, Joseph (d. 1902), "The Teeth", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Muenscher, Robert P. (d. 1862), "Pneumonia", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Phillips, Edwin (d. 1911), "Scarlatina", 1861 (Reel 9)
    - Richards, George Rawson (d. 1895), SEE listing for, 1860 (Reel 9)
    - Severance, Ebenezer Foss (d. 1886), "Peritonitis", 1860 (Reel 9)
    - Smith, Willard Burrhus (d. 1899), "Phlegmasia Dolens", 1860 (Reel 9)
    - Stangland, Eleazer Cary (d. 1888), "Diphtheria", 1860 (Reel 9)
    - Thompson, Justin Gloyd (d. 1904), "Cataract", 1860 (Reel 9)
    - Travers, Edmund Roche (d. 1899), "Typhoid Fever", 1860 (Reel 9)
    - Tweedale, Joseph Michael (d. 1910), "Anatomical Mechanism", 1860 (Reel 9)
    - Whittemore, Samuel (d. 1890), "Phthisis Pulmonalis", 1860 (Reel 10)
    - Young, Frederick Homer (d. 1916), "The Relation of Temperature to Health and Disease", 1860 (Reel 10)
  - Class of 1862
    - Brockett, Andrew Jackson (d. 1912), "Diphtheria", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Burchfield, James Penrose (d. 1904), "Auscultation and Percussion", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Chafee, Noah Fuller (d. 1912), "Respiration", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Clark, Almon (d. 1904), "Temperament", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Cory, Jerome Bonaparte (d. 1892), "The Influence of the Mind upon the Human Organism", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - DePuy, Linus (d. 1880), "Physiology of Digestion", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Dexter, Ransom (d. 1891), "Muscular Action upon Fractures", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Duncan, Titus (d. 1900), "Food", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Greene, George Washington (d. 1904), "Opium", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Gregg, John Newton (d. 1909), "Causes of Ununited Fractures", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Guthrie, James Welch (d. 1911), "Diphtheria", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Harrington, Oscar (d. 1891), "Pneumonia", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Johnson, Archibald Nesbitt (d. 1911), "The Action of Morbific Agents", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Mason, John Warner (d. 1884), "The Anatomy and Physiology of the Lungs", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Moffatt, Joseph (d. 1901), "Hygiene", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - O'Toole, Patrick William (d. 1891), "Induction of Premature Labor, its Importance and Feasibility", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Perky, Samuel (d. 1913), "Chloroform", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Pope, Horatio Gates (d. 1893), on menstrual disorders, 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Preston, Robert Henry, "The Liver, its Anatomy and Physiology", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Randolph, William Henry (d. 1893), "Chemical Forces in Nutrition", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Reed, Charles Augustus, "The General Characteristics of Fever", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Rider, Martin Ebenezer (d. 1865), "Typhoid Fever", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Root, William Walter (d. 1912), "Physiology of the Circulation", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Ruthven, George (d. 1867), "Hygiene", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Schuyler, Peter Livy (d. 1918), "The Female Organs of Generation", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Selfe, James Edwin (d. 1873), "The Physician", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Smiley, James F., "Pathology of Phthisis Pulmonalis", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Sweetland, William Palmer (d. 1905), "Typhoid Fever", 1862 (Reel 10)
    - Thacker, William Harrison (d. 1876), "Incised and Gunshot Wounds", 1862 (Reel 11)
    - Trowbridge, George Martin (d. 1885), "Philosophy of the Circulation", 1862 (Reel 11)
    - Van Duyn, Augustus Coe (d. 1907), "Influence of Imagination in Medicine", 1862 (Reel 11)
    - Vivian, Godfrey (d. 1897), "Inflammation", 1862 (Reel 11)
    - Walker, Isaac Ralph (d. 1916), "Anesthesia and Anesthetics", 1862 (Reel 11)
    - Ward, Alfred Green (d. 1889), "Signs of Pregnancy", 1862 (Reel 11)
    - Whitney, William Wallace (d. 1905), "Alcohol", 1862 (Reel 11)
    - Wigle, Joseph R. (d. 1866), "Tobacco", 1862 (Reel 11)
    - Wood, William (d. 1895), "Urea", 1862 (Reel 11)
    - Woods, Richard (d. 1880), "The Liver and its Functions", 1862 (Reel 11)
  - Class of 1863
    - Baker, Clarence Marshall (d. 1910), "Apoplexy", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Beardsley, Charles Edwin (d. 1917), "Puerperal Fever", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Brown, James Avery (d. 1885), "Acute Meningitis", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Bye, Jonah Morlan (d. 1902), "Diphtheria", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Chapin, Elijah Bennett (d. 1915), "Auscultation of the Lungs", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Davis, John (d. 1904), "The Pneumongastric Nerve", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Dewey, Edward Hooker (d. 1904), "Syphilis", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Doughty, John Henry (d. 1905), "Theories in Medicine", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Eddy, Willard (d. 1912), "The Blood", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Forbes, Elias (d. 1887), "Scarlatina", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Howell, George (1836-1909), "Cholera Infantum", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Howland, Hiram (d. 1903), "Digestion and Assimilation", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Johnson, Alexander Montgomery (d. 1882), "Caesarean Section", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Johnson, George Whitefield, "Typhoid Fever", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Kitchen, Samuel (d. 1908), "Phenomena of Inflammation", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Merrill, Charles Steele (d. 1907), "Entero-Mesenteric Fever", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Nash, Samuel Lemmy (d. 1915), "Inflammation", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Padfield, Albert Lewis (d. 1900), "The Blood and its Pathology", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Ramage, George Washington (d. 1921), "Diphtheria", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Ranney, George Emery (d. 1915), "Phthisis Pulmonalis: Is it Curable?", 1863 (Reel 11)
    - Rice, Robert Harvey (d. 1906), "Opium", 1863 (Reel 12)
    - Robinson, John Francis (d. 1864), "Science and Medicine", 1863 (Reel 12)
    - Salter, Solomon Carr (d. 1895), "Typhoid Fever", 1863 (Reel 12)
    - Sanderson, Thomas (d. 1905), "Scarlatina or Scarlet Fever", 1863 (Reel 12)
    - Sloan, Robert John (d. 1919), "Epidemic Cholera", 1863 (Reel 12)
    - Thompson, Orrin Barnes (d. 1915), "The Ganglionic System with Reference to its Connections, Histology, and Physiology", 1863 (Reel 12)
    - Van Velsor, Jacob Bright (d. 1890), "Arsenic", 1863 (Reel 12)
    - Whedon, Robert Alvin (d. 1876), "The M.D.", 1863 (Reel 12)
    - Young, William Henry (d. 1897), "Enteric Fever", 1863 (Reel 12)
    - Young, William Thompson (d. 1902), "The Murmurs of the Heart", 1863 (Reel 12)
  - Class of 1864
    - Anderson, John (d. 1867), "Diphtheria", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Anderson, Thomas William (d. 1921), "Modes of Death", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Bell, Samuel (d. 1913), "Typhoid Fever", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Chandler, William Allen, "Indigestion", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Clark, Cyrenius G. (d. 1910), "Therapeutic Application of Arsenic", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Daniels, Albert Harris (d. 1920), "The Urine in Health and Disease", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Ellison, Owen (d. 1918), "Typhoid Fever", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Eply, Charles Clark (d. 1900), "Enteritis, its Symptoms, Cause, and Treatment", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Fraser, Corwin B. (d. 1871), "Organic Life, or the Correlation of the Vital Forces", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Frothingham, George Edward (1836-1900), "Bilious Remittent Fever", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Fuller, William (d. 1896), "Malingering", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Gunn, Alexander (d. 1913), "Chloroform", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Hale, Morris (d. 1911), "Dysentery, Acute and Chronic, Its Causes, Diagnosis, Prognosis, Pathology, and Treatment", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Harris, Dwight James, "Civilization and Barbarism in their Relations to the Physical Condition of a People", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Harris, John Stuart (d. 1890), "Physiology of Respiration", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Hassler, James Power (d. 1899), "Profession of Medicine", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Hibbard, Daniel Roberts (d. 1906), "The Human Heart", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Inman, Frederick William (d. 1910), "Absorption", 1864 (Reel 12)
    - Jacobs, Benjamin Franklin (d., circa 1865), "Puerperal Fever" (Reel 12)
    - Jones, Samuel Large (d. 1865), "Dysentery", circa 1865 (Reel 12)
    - Leavitt, Clark (d. 1906), "Blood and its Functions", circa 1865 (Reel 12)
    - Ling, George Washington (d. 1917), "The Causes of Nervous Diseases", circa 1865 (Reel 12)
    - Lund, William Brown, "Relation of Pulmonal Sounds to Disease", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - McClure, Robert Law (d. 1896), "Animal Heat", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Maloney, William Bennett (d. 1881), "Abortion", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Miles, John Calvin (d. 1894), "Life-Organic and Animal", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Moore, Silas Herbert (d. 1918), "Acute Pneumonia", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - O'Neill, Arthur (d. 1899), "Stomach Digestion, Its Physiology", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Page, Edward Leland (d. 1891), "Opium", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Palmer, Elmore (d. 1909), "Erysipelas, its Treatment with Bromide", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Pinney, Charles H. (d. 1894), "Signa Encymosia", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Pittman, Herbert Benjamin (d. 1904), "Acute Pneumonia", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Prescott, Albert Benjamin (1832-1905), "Dialysis", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Putt, William Harmon (d. 1869), "Diphtheria", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Randall, Alvin Zelotes (d. 1920), "Anaemia", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Rheinfrank, John Henry (d. 1920), "Syphilis", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Russell, Ansel (d. 1867), "Cirrhosis of the Liver", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Ruthven, Duncan Gillies (d. 1897), "Opium", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Saunders, James (d. 1919), "Necrosis", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Sinclair, Lauchlin (d. 1915), "Water", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Stephenson, Robert Aldrich, "Typho-Malarial Fever", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Strong, John Thomas (d. 1895), "Inflammation", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Tewksbury, Anderson Dana, "Respiration", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Thompson, Albert (1831-1905), "Dysentery", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Tindall, Daniel Webster (d. 1904), "Etiology or Causes of Disease", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Tracy, Levi, "The Process of Nutrition", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Vickery, Richard Swanton (d. 1906), "The Duties of the Surgeon in Action", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Walker, DeLos (d. 1910), "Inflammation", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Walker, Robert Colter (d. 1900), "Inflammation", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Weaver, Leland Stutley (d. 1923), "Nutrition", circa 1865 (Reel 13)
  - Class of 1865
    - Ames, Alonzo H. (d. 1866), "Pneumonia", 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Andrews, Abiel Wood Kennedy (d. 1891), "Pyemia", 1865 (Reel 13)
    - Barber, William Marr (d. 1906), "Water", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Bartran, William Henry (d. 1905), "Changes of the Blood by Respiration", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Bentley, Michael Obilsbee (d. 1910), "Signa Encymosiae", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Biteman, James H. (d. 1865), "The Young Accoucheur in the Lying-in Chamber", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Blakeslee, Elbert Leroy (d. 1893), "The Science of Medicine", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Book, Eli E. (d. 1889), "Colitis", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Bosworth, Richard (1832-1915), "Veratrum Viride", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Burr, William Horace, "The Nutritoriis Functionibus", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Case, Henry (d. 1908), "Acute Gastritis and its Treatment", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Case, Rollin Seward, "Typho-malarial Fever and Its Treatment", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Chaffee, Charles W. (d. 1884), "Opium", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Clark, Charles Oscar (d. 1865), "Pathology with a Special Consideration of Inflammation", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Clark, Myron Sobieski, "Phthisis Pulmonalis", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Cridler, Daniel Frederick (d. 1892), "Tuberculosis", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Dean, Dexter Valverd (d. 1900), "Human Vertebrae, or, The Human Skeleton as Viewed from the Archetype Standpoint", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Dundass, Edmund Nelson (d. 1913), "Typhoid Fever", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Evans, William Harrison (d. 1912), "The Function of the Nervous System", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Fallass, William Amyr (d. 1912), "Opium; Its Therapeutical Application", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Farries, Adam Patterson (d. 1903), "Typhoid Fever", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Fletcher, Frank Edward (d. 1920), "Chloroform", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - French, Hayes Clifton (d. 1902), "Spermatorrhaea from Masturbation", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Garwood, Spencer Willard, "Syphilis", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Goodwin, Edward Westoby (1839-1929), "Opium", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Green, George Henry (d. 1903), "Tobacco", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Hall, John Alexander (d. 1895), "Hydrocele", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Hicks, John Fullerton (1838-1914), "Valvular Disease of the Heart", 1865 (Reel 14)
    - Jackson, Amzi Fuller (d. 1891), "Diphtheria", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Jaehnig, Bruno (d. 1911), "Anesthetics", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Kilbourne, Henry Sayles (d. 1910), "Chronic Diarrhea as Observed in the United States Army", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Knapp, Albert Mason (d. 1905), "Chronic Diseases", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Kurtz, George H. (d. 1916), "Diphtheria", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Lacey, John Canfield (d. 1878), "Hygiene", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Landon, Henry Bishop, "Erysipelas", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Loring, Lewis Whitney (d. 1902), "Concussion of the Brain", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - McCoy, John (d. 1921), "Excelsior Medicine", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - McHenry, George Jamison (d. 1891), "Cerebro-spinal Meningitis", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Marshall, Orville (d. 1889), "Urinology", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Martin, Patrick (d. 1896), "The Duties of the Accoucheur in Natural Labor", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Mather, Cyrus (d. 1878), "The Liver and its Functions", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Mayhew, Martin Samuel, "Typhoid Fever", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Milliken, Charles Widgery (d. 1880), "The Tongue", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Murdock, Thomas Samuel (d. 1913), "Absorption", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Newberry, Frank Dana (1840-1912), "Unmodified Variola", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Palmer, George Culver (d. 1894), "Insanity", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Parmeter, Jesse Lombard, "Inflammation and Treatment", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Patterson, Robert (d. 1908), "Typhoid Fever", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Price, Emmett Willin (d. 1910), "Hemorrhage", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Ralston, William Henry (d. 1888), "Tobacco", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Reese, Oliver Perry (d. 1917), "Acute Dysentery", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Risk, Robert Crosby (d. 1903), "Contagion", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Rowland, George (d. 1921), "Typhoid Fever", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Salisbury, Abiram Duane (1841-1909), "Necrosis", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Saunders, William Henry, "Respiration and Respiratory Organs", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Stannard, Walter Dean, "Miasmatic Fever", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Strickland, Dwight Atherton (d. 1918), "Disease, Its Nature and Causes", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Taylor, George P. (d. 1882), "The Anatomy and Physiology of the Human Heart", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Todd, George, "The Essential Articles of the Materia Medica", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Van Riper, Myron Harley (d. 1900), "Typhoid Fever", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Wallace, Hugh Lawson (d. 1868), "The Unity of the Human Species", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Ward, George James (d. 1916), "Death", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Whitman, Alvah F. (d. 1913), "Physiology and Anatomy of the Integument", 1865 (Reel 15)
    - Wiley, Cutting Bagley (d. 1888), "The 'Vis Medicatrix Naturae' of Cullen", 1865 (Reel 16)
    - Williams, James Wilson (d. 1912), "The Preservation of Health", 1865 (Reel 16)
    - Williams, Lindley Murray (d. 1911), "Pneumonia", 1865 (Reel 16)
  - Class of 1866
    - Armstrong, Charles Truman (d. 1889), "Modes of Death", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Axtell, Julien Harrison (d. 1872), "Sulphate of Quinine", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Bates, Noah, "Variola", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Berry, William Robert (d. 1893), "Lucid Intervals in Insanity", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Brewington, William Jason (d. 1890), "Prophylaxis and Hygiene", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Brock, Chauncy L., "Physical Diagnosis", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Brown, Peter Lander, "Physical Examination of the Lungs and Appendages", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Burrell, Daniel A., "Tea and Coffee", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Cheever, Henry Sylvester (d. 1877), "Catalysis", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Christie, Robert McCollough (d. 1879), "Dothienteritis", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Churchill, Owen (d. 1918), "Physical Diagnosis, Methods of; as Applied to the Chest", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Comfort, Francis Alfred (d. 1915), "Syphilis", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Daly, William Henry (d. 1901), "Sympathetic Pruritis with Special Reference to that Form Affecting the Scrotum of the Male", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Darling, Lewis (d. 1916), "Lungs, Anatomically and Physiologically Considered", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Dickinson, Julius Charles, "Belladonna", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Fairchild, Benjamin Homer (d. 1893), "Etiology of Typhoid Fever", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Fisk, Melancton Hogeboom (d. 1906), "Cholera Infantum", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Gibson, William Alexander (d. 1922), "Pneumonia", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Hadley, James W. (1821-1872), "Dyspepsia", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Hagadorn, Stephen H., "Epidemic Cholera", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Hagadorn, William Henry (d. 1898), "Generation", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Hall, Eleazer (d. 1890), "Opium", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Hamilton, Charles Alexander (d. 1900), "Inflammation", 1866 (Reel 16)
    - Hawley, Henry Alfred (d. 1897), "The Progress of Medicine", 1866 (Reel 16)